CURRICULUM VITAE PARDEEP KUMAR



+91 89680-32033, 8847359668



pardeep.kumar2116@gmail.com



H. No 230, St.No.7, Mohalla Sahibzada Fateh Singh Nagar, New Shimlapuri, Ludhiana - 141003

IUDUSTRIAL ENGINEER.

SENIOR TEXTILE DESIGNER &

Summary

I am Pardeep Kumar, an experienced professional in Textile Designing, Textile Printing, and Production. I specialize in designing and developing new textile designs for collections, drawing inspiration from prominent brands like Ann Tailor, Madewell, Navy Boot, Banana Republic, Intercity, Street One, Zara, Lucky Brand, Tommy, and the domestic market. I possess indepth knowledge of designing and weaving shawls, coupled with proficiency in software tools like Ned-graphics and Tex-tronics. My expertise lies in creating innovative textile designs and contributing to the success of fashion brands and collections, making me a valuable asset in the industry.

Kay Export Pvt Ltd. Amritsar

Oct, 2011 to July 2016

"I worked as a Textile Designer at Kay Export Amritsar Ltd.

Experience

Apollo wollen mills

Aug, 2016 to April, 2019

"I worked as a Textile Designer at Apollo Wollen Mills.

RG International

April,2019 to March,2021

"I worked as a Textile Designer at RG International

Shingora Textile Ltd.

March, 2021 to Till Date

"I worked as a Textile Designer & Industrial Eng. at ShingoraTextile Ltd."

Education

12th Passed from PSEB board.

3 years **Diploma (Textile Design)** from Punjab institute of Textile Technology, Amritsar.

B.Tech (Ind.Engg & Mgt. (Spl in TQM).

STRENGTHS

- Positive attitude
- · Hardworking and dedication to work
- Leadership quality
- Always give my best
- Communicatin skill

Skills

- Textile Designing & Printing
- Ned-graphics
- Tex-tronics
- Creating Innovative Design
- Textile Production

Reading

Making Creative designs

Travelling

Fabric Printing

Weaving

Best Knowledge About

Hobby

- Initiating continual improvement projects towards **Cost Savings**.
- Problem solving technique as Fishbone diagram & why-why analysis.
- Regular Monitoring of **Work in Process (WIP)** material.
- Responsible for **Kaizen Improvement**.
- To Analyze and reduce **Customer Complaints/ Customer Returns**.
- To maintain & improve **5S in Assembly** shop.
- Monitor & improve overall equipment efficiency.
- TAKT Time Study & Capacity Assessment as per Customer
- · Schedule.
- · Overseeing follow with internal & external customer for
- smoothproduction.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Name Pardeep Kumar
Father's Name Sh. Deena Nath
Mother's Name Smt. Parvati Devi
Date Of Birth 09-Jan-1990
Martial Status Married
Nationality Indian

If I am selected for the post applied for as per your vacancy. I may assure you sir, that I should spare no pains to justify your choice by my work and worth

Date _			Signature
Place _			